Making fun and games is anything but fun and games.
Indie Game: The Movie is a documentary film directed by Lisanne Pajot.
Follows the dramatic journeys of video game developers as they
create and release their games to the world.
It's about making video games, but at its core, it's about the
creative process, and exposing yourself through your work.
Self, played by Edmund McMillen.
Self, played by Tommy Refenes.
Self, played by Phil Fish.
Self, played by Jonathan Blow.
Self, played by Anthony Carboni.
Indie Game: The Movie is a 2012 documentary film made by
Canadian filmmakers James Swirsky and Lisanne Pajot.
The film is about the struggles of independent game developers Edmund McMillen and Tommy Refenes during the development of Super
Meat Boy, Phil Fish during the development of Fez, and also Jonathan Blow, who reflects on the success of Braid.
After two successful Kickstarter funds, interviews were conducted
with prominent indie developers within the community.
After recording over 300 hours of footage, Swirsky and Pajot decided to
cut the movie down to follow the four developers selected.
Their reasoning behind this was to show game development in the "past,
present and future" tenses through each individual's story.
The film explores themes of game, woman director,
computer programming, programmer.